Okay, so I've shown you how to do
document.getelement by ID, which allows
you to find a single element on the
page. Well, there are actually a lot of
ways that you can parse through a page.
And I'm going to show you a few of them.
So, for example, here I want to access
all of these list items. And when I
click the button, I want them all to
change to be a background color of blue
and a font color of white. So, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to say
document.getelements get elements
by tag name. And now I can supply a tag
name. Now what this does is it searches
through my entire HTML document for any
tags that are li tags. And that is all
of these right here. So I could say let
all li equal document.getelements
by tag name. What this does, you'll
notice there's an s here. It grabs every
element that matches this description
and it returns it as an array. And if
it's an array, it means we can loop
through it. So for example, we could say
for let li tag of all li all
and I can say li tagstyle
dot background color background
color equals blue. And I can say li
tagstyle
dot
color equals white. Now if I save this
and I come over here and click make them
blue, um it changes all of the text to
white and all of the background color to
blue.
So coming back over,
that is one of the ways you can get
elements by tag name. But just to show
you how many there are, you can say.get
and you can get element by ID by class
name. Uh this will give you multiple
elements that all have that class name
inside of them. So if I had this one
that had class of high and this one had
class of high, um
I could say document.getelements
get elements by class name and I could
put hi. What this would do is it would
change just those two and it went and
found them by class name and change just
those two. Um other options include get
um by name. So you could put a name on
them by tag name. Um
and so those are all just a couple of
options for how you can access things in
the HTML page. And that concludes this